https://atanet.org/ata/privacypolicy.php

Member Log-out
Click here to search the online directory »
Member Id
Password
ATA Privacy Policy
Find a Translator or Interpreter
Search for:
Translator
Interpreter
Source Language
EnglishAfrikaansAlbanianAmharicArabicArmenianAzeriBantuBelarusanBengaliBosnianBulgarianBurmeseCambodianCatalanChineseCreoleCroatianCzechDanishDariDutchEstonianFarsiFinnishFlemishFrenchGalicianGeorgianGermanGreekGujaratiHaitian KreyolHausaHebrewHindiHmongHungarianIcelandicIlokanoIndonesianItalianJapaneseJavaneseKarenKashmiriKazakhKoreanKurdishLadinoLaotianLatinLatvianLithuanianMaayMacedonianMalayMalteseMarathiMoldavianMoldovanMongolianNepaliNorwegianPashtoPolishPortuguesePortuguese - BrazilianPortuguese - EuropeanPunjabiRomanianRussianSerbianSinhaleseSlovakSloveneSomaliSpanishSwahiliSwedishTagalogTamilThaiTurkishTwiUkrainianUrduUyghurUzbekVietnameseWelshYiddishYorubaZulu
Target Language
EnglishAfrikaansAlbanianAmharicArabicArmenianAzeriBantuBelarusanBengaliBosnianBulgarianBurmeseCambodianCatalanChineseCreoleCroatianCzechDanishDariDutchEstonianFarsiFinnishFlemishFrenchGalicianGeorgianGermanGreekGujaratiHaitian KreyolHausaHebrewHindiHmongHungarianIcelandicIlokanoIndonesianItalianJapaneseJavaneseKarenKashmiriKazakhKoreanKurdishLadinoLaotianLatinLatvianLithuanianMaayMacedonianMalayMalteseMarathiMoldavianMoldovanMongolianNepaliNorwegianPashtoPolishPortuguesePortuguese - BrazilianPortuguese - EuropeanPunjabiRomanianRussianSerbianSinhaleseSlovakSloveneSomaliSpanishSwahiliSwedishTagalogTamilThaiTurkishTwiUkrainianUrduUyghurUzbekVietnameseWelshYiddishYorubaZulu
Click here for advanced options »
Why hire an ATA member?
What is a certified translation?
What's in the Current Issue?
What is School Outreach?
Procedure for Establishing a New Language Combination within ATA's Certification Program
Want to be ATA Certified?
Already ATA Certified?
Benefits of Certification
Frequently Asked Questions
Looking for More Information?
ATA Privacy Policy, Terms and Conditions, and Social Media Guidelines
ATA Privacy Policy
The American Translators Association (ATA)
respects the privacy of its members and other visitors to its website, www.atanet.org (the “Website”). ATA believes that if electronic
commerce and online activities are to flourish, consumers must be assured that
information provided online is used responsibly and appropriately. This policy describes the
type of information we collect, how the information is used and for what
purposes, to whom we disclose the information, and how we safeguard your
personal information.
If you do not agree with our policies, your
choice is to not use the ATA website or provide ATA with your information.
Collection,
Use, and Disclosure of Information
Most data ATA collects are used only
to help ATA better serve its members. It is our general policy to collect and
store only personal information that our members and visitors voluntarily provide.
Such personally identifiable information may include your name, company name,
email address, etc. (collectively referred to herein as "Personal
Information"). We do not sell, transfer, or disclose any Personal
Information we gather at our websites to any third parties without your prior
consent. There may be times when we share aggregate information—such as the
number of hits per page—with advertisers, business partners, sponsors, and
other third parties in any effort to customize or enhance the content and
advertising on our sites for our users.
Notwithstanding the foregoing, ATA
may disclose your personal information as required by law or as needed in legal
proceedings when ATA believes in good faith that disclosure is necessary to
protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate
fraud, or respond to a government request.
In addition, in the event of a
merger, acquisition, or any form of sale of some or all of our assets to a
third party, we may also disclose your personal information to the third
parties. In the event of such a transaction, the personal information held by ATA
will be among the assets transferred to the buyer.
Credit
Card Account Information
ATA does not disclose credit card
account information provided by its members and customers. When members and
customers choose to pay using their credit cards, ATA submits the information
needed to the appropriate clearinghouse through secure sites to conduct the
transactions.
Security
Measures
This website has security measures in place to protect the
loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under ATA’s control. When you
enter sensitive information (such as a credit card number) as part of the
enrollment process, we encrypt the transmission of that information using
secure socket layer technology (SSL).
When you submit information to ATA through our website, you
should be aware that your information is transmitted across the Internet and
that no method of transmission over the Internet is 100% secure. Although we
take reasonable security measures to protect your information when we receive
it, you also need to ensure you take appropriate steps to protect your
information.
Communications
From ATA
We will not send you promotional information without your
prior consent, and you can change your mind at any time by contacting us. If
you no longer wish to receive ATA’s promotional communications, you may opt-out
of receiving them by following the instructions included in each communication
or by contacting us at ata@atanet.org.
International
Website Access and Cross-Border Data Transfers
If you are visiting the ATA website
from outside the United States, your information will be transferred to,
stored, and processed in the United States where our servers are located and ATA
is based. In addition, information that ATA collects may be stored and
processed in and transferred between any of the countries in which ATA operates
to enable the use of the information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.
You agree to such cross-border transfers of personal information.
Access and
Correction/Notice to All Users
If your personally identifiable information changes, or if
you no longer desire communications or information from ATA, you may correct,
update, amend, or deactivate it by making the change by contacting us at ata@atanet.org.
You may request a copy of the information ATA holds about
you so you can correct or amend information that may be inaccurate or incomplete
by writing to ata@atanet.org. In addition, we will ask you to provide sufficient
evidence of your identity for your own protection so we can ensure that
information is being released to the correct person. We will respond to your
request to access within 30 days.
To request the deletion of your information, please contact
us by writing to ata@atanet.org.  In some cases, our
business requirements and legal obligations may prevent us from being able to
delete your information. If we are unable to delete your information, we will
let you know if we are unable to do so and why.
“Cookies”
and Internet Protocol Addresses
“Cookies”
are files that contain information created by a web server that can be stored
on a user’s hard disk for future use. ATA uses cookies only to facilitate
automated activity, store and track passwords, and review navigation patterns. Cookies
are not used to disseminate significant information about users over the
Internet or to analyze any information that users have knowingly or unknowingly
provided.
You can choose to accept or decline
cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually
modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. However, if the
User declines the attachment of any cookie, the user may not have access to the
full benefits of the Website.
We use your Internet Protocol
addresses to help diagnose problems with our server, to administer our website,
and to gather broad demographic information.
Privacy
Issues and Links to Other Sites
This website contains links to other
websites. ATA has no control over and is not responsible for the privacy
policies or content of such sites.
Social Media
Widgets
The ATA website includes social media features, such as the
Twitter, Facebook, and LinkedIn buttons that run on our site. These features
may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may
set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features
and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site.
Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the
company providing it.
Amendments
and Updates
ATA
will occasionally update this Privacy Policy. Any changes to our Privacy Policy
will be posted here so that Users will know what information we gather, how we
might use that information, and whether we will disclose it to anyone. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the
latest information on our privacy practices and this Privacy Policy.
Other
Questions
If any user has questions about this
Privacy Policy or how ATA handles collected personal information, please
contact ATA Executive Director Walter Bacak at walter@atanet.org; (703) 683-6100 ext. 3006
Updated: April 2018
TERMS AND CONDITIONS
This website and its contents are the property of the American
Translators Association (“ATA”).  This web
page states the "Terms and Conditions" for the use of the ATA website, www.atanet.org (referred as the “Website”).
By using the Website, you agree to be bound by these Terms and Conditions.  ATA may revise these Terms and Conditions at
any time by updating this posting. The terms “You” and “User” are used to refer
to anyone who is accessing the Website. If you are using the Website on behalf
of a company or other legal entity, such entity may have a separate agreement
with ATA, but you are nevertheless individually bound by these Terms and
Conditions.
IF YOU DO NOT WISH TO BE BOUND BY THESE TERMS AND CONDITIONS,
DO NOT USE THIS WEBSITE.
Ownership of Copyrights, Trademarks and Other Intellectual
Property
The
entire contents of the Website, including the text, graphics, images, logos,
button icons, HTML code, and other "material" are copyrighted by ATA
under the copyright laws of the United States.
User agrees not to remove or obscure copyright notices appearing on the
Website.  ATA grants no copyright or
ownership interests to User for any of the material and proprietary information
referred to herein belonging to ATA; limited use of the materials is permitted
only as expressly stated in the terms below.
Permission to the Website content may be granted in special
circumstances on a case-by-case basis.
Please direct any request to use content to walter@atanet.org.
Permitted
Uses of Materials
Below are
selected permitted and prohibited uses of ATA materials that are posted at the
Website.
Anyone who is doing personal, noncommercial research may
view, print material, and temporarily store materials from the Website,
provided that ATA's copyright notices are not removed and that the reuse of
material does not conflict with any of the prohibited uses below.
Any use other than as described in paragraph 1 above
requires prior written permission from ATA. Please direct any request by
emailing walter@atanet.org
User’s Link: you may link or post the link of this Website
to any document or location. ATA does not have any control over link(s) made to
any document or location at the Website, and is not responsible for any of the
content therein.
Prohibited Uses of Materials
Except for the permitted uses above, User agrees not to
reproduce, distribute, transmit (via print, fax, electronic, or other means),
modify, alter, or create derivative works of the materials contained in the
Website without prior written permission from ATA.
User agrees that materials may not be commercially exploited
or sold to third parties without prior written authorization from ATA.
User agrees that materials may not be systematically stored
on a server so as to substitute for the purchase of a subscription and/or
license agreement to/for the materials.
Name and Logo
User agrees not to use the name of the American Translators
Association, ATA, or their logos for any promotional or commercial purpose or
any other purpose without the prior written consent of ATA.
Website
Security
Interference
with Website operation: User agrees to not access or use the Website in any
manner that could damage, disable, impair or cause
undue burden on the Website and/or its host, servers, network, systems or other
users. User agrees to not attempt to interfere in any way with the operation of
the Website, that User will not transmit any virus or worm to the Website, that
User will not use any spider, robot or any other automated mechanism to access
the Website and/or its servers or systems, and that you will not engage in
flooding, spamming, mail-bombing, crashing or otherwise sending unsolicited
e-mail to other users of the Website.  User further agrees that User will
not attempt to access data that is not intended for your use, that User will
not attempt to log on to a server or account that User is not authorized to
access, and that User will not probe, scan or test the vulnerability of any
system or network related in any way to the Website without authorization.
Alteration
of Website content:  None of the
material contained on the Website (including all software, HTML code, and other
code) may be reverse-engineered, disassembled, decompiled, transcribed, stored
in a retrieval system, translated into any language or computer language,
retransmitted in any form or by any means (electronic, mechanical,
photo-reproduction, recordation, or otherwise), resold or redistributed without
the prior written permission of ATA.
Violation of
Website security: Users are prohibited from violating or attempting to violate
the security of the Website.  This site
has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse, and alteration of
the information under our control.
Please see our
Privacy Policy
for further details concerning the Website’s privacy practices.
Compliance:
User agrees to comply with all applicable laws, as well as with these Terms of
Use.  User agrees not to engage in any
unlawful or commercial activity on the Website.
Registration
and Password
Users are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of their information
and password. User is responsible for all use associated with User's
registration and the compliance with all Terms and
Conditions. User agrees to immediately notify ATA of any unauthorized use
of your password or account or any other breach of security.
Terms of Use
for Online Directories
By using ATA’s Online Directories via the Website, you hereby accept and agree
to be bound by the following terms and conditions:  The ATA Directories
and all content are proprietary to the American Translators Association.
The content of the Directories may not, in whole or in part, be reproduced,
republished, duplicated, disseminated, downloaded, entered into a computer
database, used as part of or in connection with the preparation, revision, or
confirmation of a commercial mailing, database, telephone, fax, email, or other
marketing list, or otherwise utilized, in any form or manner or by any means,
except for the user’s individual personal or professional use, or upon prior
written permission by ATA on a limited case-by-case basis.  The presence
of information about ATA members in this Directory represents only that these
individuals are members in good standing of ATA; it does not represent their
consent to allow any other professional, personal, or commercial use of the
Directory information by third parties, or to receive any marketing or related
communications, except that inquiries to obtain professional services from
potential customers or the public may be made directly to the members.
Termination
of Account
ATA reserves the right, at its sole discretion, to pursue all of
its legal remedies, including, but not limited to deletion of User's postings
from the Website and immediate termination of User's registration with the
Website or ability to access the Website and/or any other service provided to User
by ATA, upon any breach by User of these Terms and Conditions or if ATA is
unable to verify or authenticate any information User submits to the Website
for registration.  ATA shall not be liable to User nor any third party for
any termination of User’s account or access to the Website.
Waiver of Liability
ATA does not screen or censor User-generated content made available on the
Website. ATA is NOT LIABLE for any content posted on the website.  User assumes all risks associated with
dealing with other users with whom User comes in contact through the
Website.  Should a dispute arise between
User and another user, User hereby agrees to release ATA from all claims,
demand, and damages associated with such a dispute.
IN NO EVENT SHALL ATA OR ANY THIRD PARTIES MENTIONED ON THE
WEBSITE BE LIABLE FOR ANY DAMAGES WHATSOEVER (INCLUDING, WITHOUT LIMITATION,
INCIDENTAL AND CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES, LOST PROFITS OR DAMAGES RESULTING FROM
LOST DATA OR BUSINESS INTERUPTION) RESULTING FROM THE USE OR INABILITY TO USE THE
WEBSITE AND THE MATERIAL, WHETHER BASED ON WARRANTY, CONTRACT, TORT, OR ANY
OTHER LEGAL THEORY, AND WHETHER OR NOT ATA IS ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF
SUCH DAMAGES.
No Warranties
THE CONTENT THAT IS POSTED ON THE WEBSITE MAY CONTAIN INACCURACIES OR TYPOGRAPHICAL
ERRORS.  ATA MAKES NO WARRANTIES ABOUT
THE ACCURACY, RELIABILITY, COMPLETENESS, OR TIMELINESS OF THE WEBSITE, THE
MATERIAL OR OTHER POSTED CONTENT, SERVICES, SOFTWARE, TEXT, GRAPHICS, AND
LINKS.
THE WEBSITE AND MATERIAL ARE PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS"
BASIS WITHOUT ANY WARRANTIES OF ANY KIND.
ATA DISCLAIMS ALL WARRANTIES, WHETHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING THE
WARRANTY OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE, AND
NONINFRINGEMENT OF COPYRIGHT TO THE FULLEST EXTENT PERMITTED BY LAW.
ATA DOES NOT WARRANT THAT THE WEBSITE WILL OPERATE ERROR-FREE
OR THAT THE WEBSITE AND ITS SERVER ARE FREE OF COMPUTER VIRUSES OR OTHER
HARMFUL MECHANISMS.  IF YOUR USE OF THE
WEBSITE OR THE MATERIAL RESULTS IN THE NEED FOR SERVICING OR REPLACING
EQUIPMENT OR DATA, ATA IS NOT RESPONSIBLE FOR THOSE COSTS.
Links to Other Sites
The Website may contain links to third-party websites. These links are provided
solely as a convenience to User and not as an endorsement by ATA of the
third-party or the contents of such third-party websites.  Because we do not have any control over such
third-party websites, ATA is not responsible for the content of linked
third-party sites and does not make any representations regarding the content
or accuracy of materials on such third-party websites.  Linking to third-party websites is performed
at User’s own risk.
Indemnity
User agrees to defend, indemnify, and hold harmless ATA, its officers,
directors, employees and agents, from and against any claims, actions or
demands, including without limitation reasonable legal fees, resulting from
your use of the Website or your breach of the Terms of Use, including, without
limitation, your submission of content that violates third party rights or
applicable law.  ATA shall provide notice
to User promptly of any such claim, suit, or proceeding and shall assist User,
at User's expense, in defending any such claim, suit or proceeding.
Foreign Access
If User accesses this Website from outside the United States,
User does so at User's own risk.  User
agrees to comply with all applicable local rules and laws regarding the
transmission of technical data exported from the United States or the country
in which you reside.
Governing Law
These Terms and Conditions are governed by laws of the Commonwealth
of Virginia.
Jurisdiction
for any claims arising under these Terms and Conditions shall lie exclusively
with the state or federal courts within the Commonwealth of Virginia. If any provisions
of these Terms and Conditions are found to be invalid by any court having
competent jurisdiction, the invalidity of such provision shall not affect the
validity of the remaining provisions of these Terms of Use, which shall remain
in full force and effect.  No waiver of
any term of these Terms of Use shall be deemed a further or continuing waiver
of such term or any other term.
you for following the American Translators ATA (“ATA”) through our website and social
media platforms. While visiting our Facebook, LinkedIn, Twitter, or other social media sites, please keep the following guidelines in mind.
By participating in ATA’s social media platforms, you agree that you have
read and will follow these guidelines. In order to preserve a climate that
encourages both civil and fruitful dialogue, ATA reserves the right to delete
posts from participants who violate these guidelines and to suspend or
terminate the right of any participation for any reason without notice.  If you have questions about these guidelines,
please contact ATA at ata@atanet.org
ATA
SOCIAL MEDIA GUIDELINES:
The
creation of ATA-labeled social media channels on ATA’s website and third party
social media websites, and any postings and comments therein, shall not contain
or link to language or illustrations that:
Are
libelous, defamatory, obscene, threatening, offensive, demeaning, derogatory,
abusive, ad hominem, or off-topic
Are
solely for commercial purposes
Endorse
any candidate or office holder or partisan political position
third party’s privacy rights, proprietary rights, or any other applicable
local, state, national, or international law
Degrade
others on the basis of gender, race, class, ethnicity, national origin,
religion, sexual preference, disability, or other classification
Keep in mind that information
posted on these social media channels is available for all to see, and comments
are subject to defamation, antitrust, and other laws. ATA will not be held liable
for any injury or damage resulting from statements posted on ATA-labeled social
media channels.
THE LEGAL STUFF
By
posting materials to ATA-labeled social media and ATA’s website, mentioning ATA in your public social media
posts, or voluntarily providing your social media handle to ATA, you grant
to ATA the nonexclusive, world-wide, transferable right and license to display,
copy, publish, distribute, transmit, print, and use such information or other
material in any way and in any medium, including but not limited to print or
electronic form.
ATA
is not responsible for the content of third party social media websites and
does not make any representations regarding the content or accuracy of
materials on them.  Before posting on ATA-labeled
social media channels, please review and abide by the terms of use and privacy
policy of the specific social media website.
The opinions of ATA social media
channel creators, moderators, posters, and commentators, are their own, and not
necessarily that of ATA.
With these rules and guidelines in
mind, happy posting!
We use cookies to give you the best experience on the ATA website. You can find out more about how we use cookies in the
ATA Privacy Policy.
